Guide to the Mabel Dodge Luhan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1859-1951; Series III; 7.3; (18 boxes)
  - FAMILY
    - Reeder, "Admiral", [1899?] (Box 70, Folder 1894)
      Studio portrait by Photographie Florian
    - Sealcherd, Jack and E.B.S. Wood, [ca. 1880s] (Box 70, Folder 1895)
    - Usher, Dixie, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1896)
    - Winslow, George, 1875 Jan 4 (Box 70, Folder 1897)
    - ----, Henry, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1898)
    - [Empty folder] (Box 70, Folder 1899)
    - Groups of people, 1920, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1900)
      With Albertson and Ganson families, Montagues, and Field carriage
    - Unidentified, 1913, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1901)
  - FRIENDS AND OTHERS
    - Adrian, Gilbert, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1902)
      With Janet and unidentified others, and portraits by Frank Tanner and John Engstead
    - [Adrian?], Janet, n.d.
      Portrait by John Engstead
    - Albertson, Hazel and family (Box 70, Folder 1904)
    - Albertson, [Miriam or Rachel?], n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1905)
    - Albertson, Wyatt, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1906)
    - Alfaro, ----, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1907)
    - Angulo, Jaime de, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1908)
      With Guiomar de Angulo
    - Angulo, Nancy, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1909)
      With [Guimar de Angulo?]
    - Armijo, Edwardo, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1910)
    - Bashkirtseff, Marie, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1911)
    - Baumann, Gus, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1912)
    - Bender, Albert M. (Albert Maurice) (Box 70, Folder 1913)
      Photograph by Edward Weston
    - Bistram, Marion, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1914)
    - Black, LaVerne G., n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1915)
    - Boke, Richard, 1930-40s (Box 70, Folder 1916)
      With Sara Boke
    - Boke, Sally and child, 1930s (Box 70, Folder 1917)
    - Boke, Sara, [ca. 1936-37] (Box 70, Folder 1918)
    - Boyd, E., n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1919)
    - Boyd, Fred, 1914, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1920)
    - Boyesen, Bayard, n.d.
    - Bradley, ---- and unidentified man and woman, 1911 (Box 70, Folder 1921)
    - Brett, Dorothy, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1922-1923)
      With Angelino Ravagli and unidentified others
    - Bright, Miriam, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1924)
      With Ned Bright
    - Bright, Ned, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1925)
    - Brill, A. A. (Abraham Arden), n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1926)
    - Brinig, Myron, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1927)
    - Brisbane, Arthur, n.d.
    - Broglie, "Princess" de, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1928)
    - Bynner, Witter, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1929-1930)
      With Harvey Fergussen and unidentified man
    - Carney, Nora M., n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1931)
    - Cary, Seward, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1932)
    - Chávez, Carlos, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1933)
    - Cheetan, ----, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1934)
    - Collier, Charles, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1935)
    - Collier, Donald, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1936)
      With John and Lucy Collier and "Smudge" Draper
    - Collier, John Jr., 1939
    - Cristina, Maria, 1929-37, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1937)
      With Maria [Jr.?] and child
    - Dasburg, Alfred, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1938)
      With "Johnson" and unidentified others
    - Dasburg, Andrew, 1914, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1939)
      With Ida Rauh
    - Davidson, Jo, 1925, 1934 (Box 71, Folder 1940)
    - Day, Kate, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1941)
    - Day, Mr. and Mrs. (Box 71, Folder 1942)
    - Dodge, Edwin Sherrill, [ca. 1900-10] (Box 71, Folder 1943)
      Includes studio portraits by H.A.V. Coles and Numa Blanc fils
    - Draper, "Smudge", n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1944)
      With unidentified children
    - Duncan, Elizabeth, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1945)
    - Duncan, Isadora, 1915, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1946)
      Portraits by Arnold Genthe
    - Duncan, Senta, 1921 (Box 71, Folder 1947)
    - Duncan School dancers, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1948)
    - Eastman, Max, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1949)
    - [Eben?], ----, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1950)
    - Feshin, Nikolai Ivanovich, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1951)
    - Folwell, Bainbridge, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1952)
    - Folwell, Roger, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1953)
    - Foote, Mary, 1907, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1954)
      With Alfred Dasburg and others
    - Francis, Kay, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1955)
    - Given, Thelma, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 1956-1958)
      With unidentified girl
    - Goringe, Kay, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1959)
    - Gregory, Harold Anthony, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1960)
    - Gruening, Mary, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1961)
    - Gurdjieff, Georges Ivanovitch, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1962)
    - Hamlin, Charles and Emily (Box 72, Folder 1963)
      Photograph by Frank Schifferle
    - Hamlin, Jack and Eve (Box 72, Folder 1964)
    - Hamlin, Martha, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1965)
      With "Gav" vis der Hooff and parents
      Includes studio portraits by Press Studios
    - Hamlin, Mary, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1966)
    - Harris, Henri, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1967)
    - Heath, Ogden, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1968)
    - Heiroth, Alexander de, 1929 (Box 72, Folder 1969)
    - Henderson, Alice Corbin (Box 72, Folder 1970)
      With Natalie Henderson
    - Henderson, Natalie (Box 72, Folder 1971)
    - Higgins, Joan, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1972)
    - Hoffman, Malvina, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1973)
    - Hopper, James, 1930 May 20 (Box 72, Folder 1974)
    - Hughes, Langston and Una Jeffers (Box 72, Folder 1975)
      With Noël Sullivan
    - Hurst, Fannie, 1938 (Box 72, Folder 1976)
      Photograph by Kaiden [Kazanjiin?]
    - James, Rebecca Salsbury, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1977)
    - Jeffers, Robinson, 1929-39, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1978)
      With Frieda Lawrence and photograph by Lester Donahue
    - [Jeffers, Una?], n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1979)
    - Jelliffe, Belinda (Box 72, Folder 1980)
    - Johnson, Grace, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1981)
    - Johnson, Walter Willard ("Spud"), n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1982-1983)
      With Charles [Johnson?] and unidentified man
    - Jones, Robert Edmond (Box 72, Folder 1984)
    - Kahlo, Frida
      See: Rivera, Diego, Box 73, folder 2025
    - Kepner, Arch, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1985)
    - Kiker, [Henry?], n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1986)
    - Kiker, Mary Pollard, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1987)
    - [Kuster?], Gabrielle, [1904-05?] (Box 72, Folder 1988)
      With child
    - [Kuster?], ----, [1904-05?] (Box 72, Folder 1989)
    - Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), 1929, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1990-1991)
      With Aldous Huxley, Frieda Lawrence, Ida Rauh, Clarence Thompson and others
      Includes photographs by Bob Davis
    - Lawrence Frieda von Richthofen, 1950, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1992-1993)
      With Angelino Ravagli and unidentified man
      Includes photographs by Carl Van Vechten and Andre Wiedmann
    - Lee, Arthur, 1910, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1994)
    - Lescaze, William, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1995)
    - Levine, Arthur N., 1939, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1996)
    - Light, Gertrude, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1997)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1915 Nov 27
    - Litvinov, Ivy, 1929-32 (Box 72, Folder 1998)
      With family
    - Lujan, John, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 1999)
    - [MacKaye?], Arvia, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2000)
      With "Carolyn"
    - MacKaye, Percy, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2001)
      Includes photograph by Cady Wells
    - MacLeod, Tantine, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2002)
    - Marcy, Everett, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2003)
    - Marcy, "Lessie", n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2004)
    - Markowitz, ----, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2005)
      Photograph by Alfred Stieglitz
    - Marry, Tessie, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2006)
    - Meyers, Ralph, 1922, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2007)
    - Meyers, Rowena, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 2008)
      With "Gisella," daughter and unidentified child
    - Myerberg, Adrienne, [1930s] (Box 72, Folder 2009)
      With Michael and Toni Myerberg
    - Myerberg, Toni, [1930s] (Box 73, Folder 2010)
    - O'Conner, Charles, 1935 May (Box 73, Folder 2011)
    - Older, Fremont, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2012)
    - Oliver, Jack, 1935 (Box 73, Folder 2013)
    - Orage, A. R. (Alfred Richard) and son (Box 73, Folder 2014)
    - O'Shea, Shawn, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2015)
    - Otis, Bina, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2016)
    - Otis, Raymond (Box 73, Folder 2017)
    - Pelton, Agnes, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2018)
    - Prinzhorn, Hans, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2019)
    - Rauh, Ida, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2020)
    - Ravagli, Angelino, 1950 Aug 17 (Box 73, Folder 2021)
      Photograph by Carl Van Vechten
    - Reed, John, [1917?], n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2022)
    - Reh, Emma and "Las Casas" (Box 73, Folder 2023)
    - Riggs, Lynn, 1931 Jun 13 (Box 73, Folder 2024)
      Studio portrait by Vandamm
    - Rivera, Diego, 1924, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2025)
      With Frida Kahlo
      Includes photograph by Edward Weston
    - Robinson, Leighton, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2026)
    - Rogers, "Bobby", [1917?] (Box 73, Folder 2027)
    - Rudhyar, [Dane?], n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2028)
    - Scripps, Peggy, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2029)
    - Scudder, Janet, 1910 (Box 73, Folder 2030)
    - [Shevky?], Miriam, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2031)
      With [Trinidad?]
    - [Shevky?], Richard, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2032)
    - Smith, E. Deming and family, 1925 (Box 73, Folder 2033)
    - Smith, Patricia, 1937, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2034)
    - Speyer, "Mrs." Walter M., n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2035)
    - Sprague, Alice, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2036)
      With Clarence Thompson
    - Steffens, Lincoln, n.d.
    - Sterne, Maurice, 1915-17, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2037)
      Includes photograph by Arnold Genthe
    - Stokowska, Evangeline, n.d.
      Studio portrait by Lee Pearly
    - Stokowski children, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2038)
    - Sturtzel, Steve, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2039)
    - Sullivan, Noël, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2040)
    - Tant, Barry, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2041)
    - Tenios, ----, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2042)
    - Tenios, ----, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2043)
    - Thompson, Clarence, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2044)
      With Tony Archuleto and unidentified others
    - Thursby, Alice, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2045)
    - Tregor, Nison, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2046)
      With Tryanovsky, Zikorcky and artwork
    - Van Vechten, Carl, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2047)
    - Walde, Ernest Stewart, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2048)
      Studio portraits by Gillman & Co.
    - Waters, Frank, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2049)
      With Steve Sturtzel
    - Weaver, Elizabeth, [ca. 1920-30] (Box 73, Folder 2050-2051)
      With "Hazel" and unidentified others
    - Wells, Cady, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2052)
    - Whitfield, Emily, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2053)
    - Whitfield, Raoul, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2054)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1938, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2055)
      Includes photographs of Wilder soirée by K. W. Hermann, with Eithna Golden, Mary Miller, Patricia Smith and others
    - Witt, Lee, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2056)
    - Young, Ella, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 2057)
    - Young-Hunter, John and unidentified men (Box 73, Folder 2058)
    - Young-Hunter, Mary and unidentified man (Box 73, Folder 2059)
    - ----, Dorothy and unidentified woman, 1929 Jul (Box 74, Folder 2060)
    - ----, Edwardo, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2061)
      With wife
    - ----, [June?], n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2062)
    - ----, Paoli, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2063)
    - ----, Tony and unidentified woman (Box 74, Folder 2064)
    - ----, Violette, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2064a)
    - Groups of people, 1940, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2065)
      With Dorothy Brett, Witter Bynner, Lázaro Cárdenas, Donald Collier, Alfred Dasburg, Grace Johnson, Spud Johnson, D. H. and Frieda Lawrence, Arvia [MacKaye?], Maurice Sterne and others
      Includes photograph by Miguel Flores
    - Unidentified, 1907-48, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2066-2074)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 2075-2082)
  - NATIVE AMERICAN INDIANS
    - Individuals
      - Archuleta, Juan, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2083)
        See also: Mounted Photographs, Folder [2], Box 77, folder 2131
      - Archuleta, Tony, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2084)
      - Awa Tsireh, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2085)
      - Castillano, Luis, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2086)
      - [Concha?], Eliseo, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2087)
      - Concha, John, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2088)
      - Concha, ----, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2089)
      - Marcus, John, 1933 Jul 15 (Box 75, Folder 2090)
      - Navaho Chief, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2091)
      - Raina, Manuel, 1933 Jul 15 (Box 75, Folder 2092)
      - Sun Priest, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2093)
      - Vijil, Juan, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2094)
      - Zuni Priest, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2095)
      - ----, Albidia, 1933-35, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2096)
        Includes photographs by Carl Van Vechten
      - ----, Emily, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2097)
      - ----, Fernando (Box 75, Folder 2098)
      - ----, Jose, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2099)
      - ----, Thomacito, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2100)
      - ----, Trinidad, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2101)
        See also: Brett, Dorothy, Box 71, folders 1922-1923
        See also: Mounted Photographs, Folder [3], Box 77, folder 2132
      - Unidentified, 1922-33, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2102-2110)
        Includes photographs by Ralph Meyers and Carl Van Vechten
      - Unidentified, 1935, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 2111)
    - Groups
      - Buffalo Dance, 1914, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 2112)
      - Corn Dance (Box 76, Folder 2113)
      - [Eagle Dance], n.d. (Box 76, Folder 2114)
      - "Horse fun", n.d. (Box 76, Folder 2115-2117)
        Includes photographs by Jane Hardy
      - [Zuni Dance?], n.d. (Box 76, Folder 2118)
      - [Zuni Mudheads], n.d. (Box 76, Folder 2119)
      - Unidentified dances, 1931, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 2120-2123)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 2124-2129)
  - MOUNTED PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Folder [1], n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2130)
    - Folder [2], n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2131)
    - Folder [3], 1917-20, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2132)
      With Antonio Pena, Tony Romero, Martin Vigil and Trinidad
    - Folder [4], n.d.
    - Folder [5], 1917-21, n.d.
    - Folder [6], n.d.
  - PLACES
    - California
      - Agnes Pelton's studio, Cathedral City, 1942 (Box 77, Folder 2133)
      - Biltmore Hotel, Santa Barbara, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2134)
      - Carmel coastline, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2135)
      - Hut in Cathedral City, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2136)
      - [Shevky house?], Mill Valley, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2137)
      - Tor House, Carmel, 1937, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2138)
      - Yosemite, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2139)
        Photographs by Ansel Adams
    - Italy
      - Olive trees near Tivoli, 1934 Jun 8 (Box 77, Folder 2140)
        Photographs by Carl Van Vechten
      - Venice, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2141)
      - Villa Curonia, Florence, 1935, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2142-2146)
      - Villa Mirenda, Florence (postcard) (Box 78, Folder 2147)
      - Vineyard near Amalfi, 1934 Jun 10 (Box 78, Folder 2148)
      - Other, 1934 Jun 9 (Box 78, Folder 2149)
    - New York
      - 184 Delaware Avenue, Buffalo, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2150)
      - 23 Washington Square, New York, 1916, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2151)
      - Finney Farm, Croton-on-Hudson, [1914-15?] (Box 78, Folder 2152)
      - [Washington Square Park?], New York, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2153)
      - "Winding River," Youngstown (Box 78, Folder 2154)
    - Taos and Southwest
      - Biltmore Hotel, Arizona, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2155)
      - Blue Lake, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2156)
      - Chapel, placita de Taos, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2157)
      - Church of Jesus Christ of the Latter-day Saints, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2158)
      - Don Fernando Hotel, Taos (Box 78, Folder 2159)
      - Los Gallos, Taos, 1933-50, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2160-2168)
        Includes photographs by Ansel Adams, Jane Hardy, Ernst Knee, Laura Gilpin, Carl Van Vechten and Cady Wells
      - Los Gallos, Taos, 1933-50, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2169-2173)
      - Governor's Palace, Santa Fe, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2174)
      - Grand Canyon (Box 79, Folder 2175)
      - Holy Cross Hospital, Taos, 1951, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2176)
        See also: La Posta, Taos, Box 79, folder 2182
      - Lawrence's ranch, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2177)
      - Menby house, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2178)
      - Mission Church, Taos, 1935 Jul 15 (Box 79, Folder 2179)
      - Mt. Wheeler, Utah, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2180)
      - Museum, Santa Fe, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2181)
      - La Posta, Taos, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2182)
        See also: Holy Cross Hospital, Box 79, folder 2176
      - Pueblo, Taos, 1924-50, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2183-2184)
        Includes photographs by Leighton Robinson and Carl Van Vechten
      - Ranchos de Taos church, 1933-50, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2185)
      - Raymond Otis's house, Santa Fe (Box 79, Folder 2186)
      - Taos Plaza Bandstand (Box 79, Folder 2187)
      - Tony Luhan's house, Taos, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2188)
      - Trading Co., San Ysidro, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2189)
      - Twining Canyon, [1948?]
        Photograph by Laura Gilpin
      - U.S. Post Office, Taos, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2190)
        Photograph by Ernst Knee
      - Unidentified, 1924-50, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2191-2199)
        Includes photographs by Laura Gilpin, Leighton Robinson and Carl Van Vechten
      - Unidentified, 1933, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 2200-2201)
        Includes photographs by Ernst Knee and Sonya Noskowiak
    - Other
      - Abbott house, Taxco, Mexico, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2202)
      - County Mayo, Ireland, 1929 (Box 80, Folder 2203)
        Photograph by [Una?] Jeffers
      - Dominica, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2204)
      - Memphis skyline, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2205)
      - Mexico, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2206)
      - Monhegan, [Maine?], n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2207)
      - Nebeltreiben im Gebirge, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2208)
      - Oklahoma City view, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2209)
      - Saint Moritz, Switzerland (Box 80, Folder 2210)
      - San Angel Inn, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2211)
      - Villa Rurik, Helsinki, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2212)
      - Unidentifed houses, 1931, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2213-2214)
      - Unidentified, 1934, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2215)
  - ARTWORK
    - [Blanche, Jacques-Emile?]: painting of Nijinsky, 1913 (Box 80, Folder 2216)
    - Bradley, Horace: paintings, [1912?] (Box 80, Folder 2217)
    - Brett, Dorothy: [painting?], 1929 (Box 80, Folder 2218)
    - Chase, William Merritt: painting, [ca. 1908] (Box 80, Folder 2219)
    - Craig, James P.: painting, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2220)
    - [Davidson?], Jo: sculpture, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2221)
    - Fabbricotti, Contessa Emma: pastel of Eleonora Duse, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2222)
    - Feshin, Nikolai Ivanovich: paintings of Dorothy Brett, Willa Cather, Mary Hamlin, Spud Johnson, Elizabeth Shepley Sergeant and Ella Young (Box 80, Folder 2223)
    - Foote, Mary: painting of Stephen Haweis, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2224)
    - Haweis, Stephen: paintings, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2225)
    - Johnson, G. M.: drawings, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2226)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge: sculpture, 1915 (Box 80, Folder 2227)
    - Scudder, [Janet?]: sculpture, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2228)
      Photograph by Bogart Studio
    - Sloan, Blanding: painting (Box 80, Folder 2229)
    - Sterne, Maurice: paintings and sculpture (Box 80, Folder 2230)
    - Tregor, Nison: sculpture, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2231)
    - Ufer, Walter: painting, 1919 (Box 80, Folder 2232)
    - Ullman, Eugene Paul: paintings, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2233)
    - Wurtzel, Marian: paintings, 1940, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2234)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2235-2236)
  - OTHER
    - Animals, 1936-37, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 2237-2243)
      Includes photographs by Laura Gilpin and Una Jeffers
    - D. H. Lawrence's grave, Vence, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 2244)
    - "De Soto" reflection, 1935 Aug 2 (Box 81, Folder 2245)
    - Glass carafe and bowl (Box 81, Folder 2246)
      Photograph by Ansel Adams
    - Hal Roach's Northrup airplane, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 2247)
    - Hunting party, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 2248)
    - Medallions of [MDL?] and unidentified figure (Box 81, Folder 2249)
    - Nudes, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 2250)
      Includes photograph by Bill Spaulding
  - CUT FILM NEGATIVES
    There are approximately 500 cut film negatives. A survey of the negatives suggests that they correspond to the prints in Series III. The negatives are restricted. For further information, see the appropriate curator.
- Scrapbooks, 1912-1949; Series IV; 21.25; (17 boxes)
  Series IV, Scrapbooks, is arranged alphabetically by title.
  - "Armory Show", 1913-14, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 2251)
  - "Edge of Taos Desert", 1937-38, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 2252)
    Includes letters to MDL from Harcourt, Brace & Company, Elsie Worthington Clews Parsons, Belinda Jelliffe, Carl Hovey and Lew Barrington Wallace
  - "European Experiences", 1935-36, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2253)
    Includes letters to MDL from J. Paget-Fredericks, Albert Bender and The Nation
  - "History of Taos & Its Artists", 1947-49, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2254)
    Includes letters to MDL from James W. Young, Birger Sandzén, Oscar E. Berninghaus, Sonya Levien, and Duell, Sloan & Pearce
    Article: "Construction Techniques Suffer as Organic Checks and Balances Neglected"
  - "Intimate Memories and Letters", 1932-35, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 2255)
  - "Lawrence", 1930-33, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 2256)
    Includes copies of letters to MDL from Alfred A. Knopf, Clarence [Thompson?], Elizabeth Shepley Sergeant, Marie T. Garland, and Blanche "Shoemacher" Wagstaff
    Articles: "The Lawrence I Knew..." "La mission de D. H. Lawrence à Taos" "D. H. Lawrence à Taos"
  - "Lawrence Vol. II", 1933-36, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 2257)
    Includes letter to MDL from Alfred A. Knopf
  - "Lawrence Vol. III", 1937-39, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 2258)
    Open letter: ["Dear Haniel Long..."]
  - "Many Inventions! 1914", 1912-14, n.d. (Box 90, Folder 2259)
    Includes letter to MDL from George Creel
    Article: "The Tannenbaum Case"
  - "Misc. Vol. I", 1913-37, n.d. (Box 91, Folder 2260)
    Articles: "Mabel Writes About Three Young Men in a Pool" "Orientalism Comes West on East's Power" "Mabel Dodge Talks on Mothers of Men" "Fear, Brutal Parasite, Feeds our Soul till it Dies" "Mabel Dodge Writes on Keeping Step with Time" "Mabel Dodge's Article on "Pass'd! for Us..." "Love is a Big Energy Dynamo" "Who Wants Pictures?" "Mabel Dodge Writes on Working for a Living" "Choose Idol, then Love Him for Ever" "Mabel Dodge Writes on Quilts" "Mabel Dodge Writes About Your Faculty of Attention" "Mabel Dodge Writes on Strange Mary MacLane" "Mabel Dodge Talks About the In-Between Times" "Mabel Dodge Writes on Three Kinds of People" "Mabel Dodge Writes About More Light in the Home" "Mabel Dodge Writes About Adopting a Baby" "Mabel Dodge Writes on Love and Ownership" "Beware the Grip of Paganism!" "Mabel Dodge Writes About the Unconscious" "Men and Girls Spend All Energy Well" "Mabel Dodge Writes About Looking Ahead" "Mabel Dodge Talks About a Corner in the Hills" "Isadora Duncan" "Molly O'Shea" "Ella Young and the Fairies" "Max Eastman in Carmel"
  - "Misc. Vol. II", 1936-39, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2261)
    Includes letter to MDL from John Collier with carbon from Collier to Chauncey S. Goodrich
  - "Movers & Shakers", 1934-37, n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2262)
    Includes letters to MDL from Town & Country, John Stuart, Granville Hicks and Harcourt, Brace & Company
  - "Paterson Strike", 1913-14, n.d. (Box 94, Folder 2263)
    Includes corrected manuscript "The International Exhibition of Modern Art"
  - "Taos (etc)", 1913-37, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 2264)
    Articles: "Market Day in the Plaza" "Dia de Merca do en la Plaza" "More Taos Advertising" "Taos the Trading Post"
  - "Taos Vol. II", 1938-39, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 2265)
    Article: "Plan to Re-establish Old Market Days in Taos"
  - "Winter in Taos", 1935-38, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 2266)
  - Untitled, 1914-28, n.d. (Box 98, Folder 2267)
    Includes drawings and watercolor